Encounters are mysterious! But Osaka is even more so!
لقاءات البشر مغلّفة بالغموض، وأوساكا تلفّها طبقات أكثر حتّى
I'm so glad I'm with you!
!أنا مسرورٌ حقّاً لكوني معك
Today is a sixty-minute Naniwa special
!اليوم حلقة نانيوا من 60 دقيقة
filled with incidents and mystery!
!حلقة خاصّة، كما قضيّتها وألغازها
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ دماغه لبالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
This is the incident in Toyonaka.
هذه الحادثة في مدينة تويوناكا
And this is last week's incident in Harakata.
وهذه التي وقعت الأسبوع الفائت في هيراكاتا
There were no witnesses to these killings,
لا شهود على جريمتي القتل هاتين
and they're dozens of kilometers away.
ويفصل بين الموقعين عدّة كيلومترات
We're checking into how these two victims are connected,
نحن نتحرّى في وجود أيّ صلة ،بين الضحيّتين حالياً
but they still share nothing in common.
لكن لا شيء مشترك بينهما حتّى الآن
Chief Detective Toyama, Osaka Police Headquarters
كبير المحقّقين توياما قيادة شرطة أوساكا
There's only one thing: the knife.
فقط شيء واحد
I don't know why, but they were both stabbed in the heart,
لا أعرف السبب، لكنّهما طُعنا في القلب
through their wallets in their jackets.
عبر المحفظة في جيب معطفيهما
Have you told the media about this?
هل أخبرت الإعلام عن هذا؟
No, not the wallet part.
كلا، تكتّمت على أمر المحفظة
That means the second killing wasn't some moron's copycat attack.
أي أنّ حادثة القتل الثانية لم يكن فعلة مقلّد أحمق
Correct, it was definitely the same person.
أجل، كان نفس الشخص بلا شكّ
Serial murders...
...سلسلة جرائم قتل
If the murders are at random, it'll cause a panic.
إذا كانت عشوائية، فستثير الهلع
Toyama... You'd best be extra careful.
توياما، حاذر ألّا ترتكب أيّ زلّة
Hattori Heizo Osaka Chief of Police
هاتّوري هيزو قائد شرطة أوساكا
Yes, I know.
أجل، أعي ذلك
That's the Tennoji Zoo!
هذه حديقة حيوانات تينّوجي
That's the Osaka Dome!
وتلك قبّة أوساكا
And this is the Tsutenkaku Tower!
وهذا برج تسوتينكاكو
Whadya think? Osaka's nice, huh?!
ما رأيكم؟ أليست أوساكا رائعة؟
Yeah! This is a great view!
بلى، المنظر رائع
I dunno, it's no different from the Tokyo Tower...
لكن لا يبدو مختلفاً عن برج طوكيو
Don't be dumb! Don't compare this with that tasteless red thing!
أحمق! لا تقارنه بذاك الشيء ا!لأحمر عديم الذوق
The Tsutenkaku and the new world all around it
تسوتينكاكو هذا وحيّ "شين سينكاي" المحيط به
are brimming with the Osakans' humanity!
!يشعّان بطبيعة أهل أوساكا
It's almost like downtown Tokyo!
تبدو كوسط مدينة طوكيو
How about some food now?
ما رأيك بأن نتناول الطعام الآن؟
Just a little longer! I'm waiting for someone!
انتظروا قليلاً، سيأتي أحدهم لاصطحابنا
Fine, guess I'll have a smoke.
ليس باليد حيلة، سأذهب لتدخين لفافة
Hey, Hattori.
هاتّوري
Tell me why you called me to Osaka.
أخبرني بسبب استدعائك لي إلى أوساكا؟
Huh? You're concerned about that?
ماذا؟ أكنت قلقاً حيال ذلك؟
You have another real reason, right?
لديك دافع آخر حقيقيّ، أليس كذلك؟
No, no! There's really no work this time!
كلا، كلا! لا عمل هذه المرّة حقّاً
I just thought I'd show you guys around Osaka!
خطر لي أن أطلعكم على أوساكا لا أكثر
There's no telling when you'll die, after all.
فلا يعرف المرء متى يفارق الحياة
W-What's that mean?
ما-ما قصدك بذلك؟
I had a bad dream...
راودني حلمٌ غريب
Dream?
حلم؟
Yeah... it happens when we catch a bad guy.
أجل، نكون فيه على وشك الإمساك بالمجرم
But he winds up stabbing and killing you instead!
لكنّه يطعنك في المقابل
Hey, now! Don't kill people on your own!
!أنت، لا تقتل الآخرين من تلقاء نفسك
There you have it. So just enjoy Osaka!
حسناً، هذا ما عليه الأمر، لذا فلتستمتع بأوساكا
Sorry! Heiji-kun!
!آسف يا هيجي-كن
Sakata Yusuke (26) Tojiri Police Detective, Section 1
(ساكاتا يوسكي (26 محقّق في مركز توجيري، القسم الأوّل
I'm Sakata of the Osaka Police, Tojiri Station!
أنا ساكاتا من مركز توجيري لشرطة محافظة أوساكا
Sorry for being so late!
أعتذر على التأخير
Why is a police detective here?
لمَ أتى محقّق شرطة هنا؟
My old man said that if Mori-han's coming to Osaka,
أخبرني أبي أنّه في حال ،قدوم العمّ موري إلى أوساكا
he should have a proper tour guide!
فعليّ أن أصطحبه في جولة إرشاديّة لائقة
Huh? Where is my old man? He said he was going to stop by.
ماذا؟ أين أبي؟ قال أنّه سيمرّ بنا
The chief is busy in a meeting about the incidents.
حضرة الرئيس مشغولٌ في اجتماع بشأن تلك القضيّة
"The incidents"?
تلك القضيّة؟
So, did you get the car?
إذاً، هل جهّزت تلك السيّارة؟
Of course!
!بالطبع
I did just like you asked and borrowed the Tojiri station's best one!
فعلتُ ما طلبتَه منّي، وأخذت أفضل !سيّارة في مركز توجيري
H-Hey, now. Don't tell me this car is...
مهلك، أيمكن أنّ تلك السيّارة
Well, let's go!
!هيّا، هلمّ بنا
Isn't this the best?! Cop cars are great!
أليس هذا رائعاً؟
You can pass other cars even in traffic jams!
يمكنك تجاوز بقيّة السيّارات !حتى في الازدحام المروري
So, where would you like to go, guests?
إذاً أين مقصدكم يا حضرة الضيوف؟
Tell me...
...أنت
Are you making us tour Osaka in this thing?!
!أتخبرنا أن نجوب أوساكا بهذه السيّارة؟
Huh? You don't like it? It's brand new!
ماذا؟ لم تنل إعجابك؟
No, that's not what he means...
...لا، ليس الأمر هكذا
It feels like we're being arrested, so it's kind of embarrassing.
يبدو أنّنا معتقلون، فالأمر مُحرج قليلاً
Oh, don't worry about that! You haven't done anything wrong!
!لا تقلقوا حيال ذلك! لم تقدموا على أيّ أمر سيّئ
Hold your heads high!
!فيمكنكم رفع رؤوسكم بفخر
Whadya think?! This is real udon!
!ما رأيكم؟ هذا هو الأودون الحقيقيّ
The soup's so clear you can see the bottom!
الحساء صافٍ بحيث ترون قاع الوعاء
Yeah, you can!
!معك حقّ
It's a light flavor, but good!
نكهته خفيفة، لكنّه لذيذ
Tastes like nothing.
لا مذاق له
Oh, Heiji! Who's she? A new girlfriend?
هيجي! من هذه الفتاة؟ حبيبة جديدة؟
Does it seem that way?
أيبدو كذلك؟
No! I'm just a regular Tokyo--
...كلا! أنا زائرة عاديّة من طوكيو
What is it?
ما الأمر؟
I suddenly got a chill...
...شعرتُ ببرودةٍ ما
So, where to next?
إذاً، أين تريدون الذهاب تالياً؟
Hmm, the next thing Osaka is famous for is...
حسناً، الشيء الثاني الذي تتميّز ...به أوساكا بعد الأودون
Yum!
!لذيذ
This takoyaki is great!
أليس هذا التاكوياكي لذيذاً جدّاً؟
I've never had ones with such big octopus!
لم يسبق ورأيته يحتوي أخطبوطاً كبيراً كهذا
What is it?
ما الأمر؟
Nothing... it just feels like someone's been watching me...
لا شيء، أشعر كأنّ أحدهم يراقبني لفترة فقط
Oh, don't worry about it and eat up!
!لا تقلقي حيال ذلك، وكلي فحسب
I can't take my eyes off you!
!لا أستطيع الإهمال معكما
I thought you were on a diet, Ran-neechan?
ظننتُ أنّكِ في حمية
Okonomiyaki? Why didn't you say so before the takoyaki?
أوكونومياكي؟َ لمَ لم تذكروا !ذلك قبل التاكوياكي؟
We already passed a great place I know!
المطعم اللذيذ الذي أعرفه شمال المكان من هنا
We're going the wrong way! We can't get there on Midosuji!
نحن في الطريق المعاكس! لا يمكننا !الذهاب هناك عبر ميدوسوجي
Osaka is full of one-way roads,
،أوساكا مليئة بالطرق أحاديّة الاتّجاه
so you often have to go way out of your way!
لذا اعتماداً على موقعك، قد يتعيّن عليك أخذ منعطف طويل
In that case, shall I show them a nearby place I know?
في تلك الحالة، هل أصطحبهم إلى مكان قريب أعرفه؟
It's a good thing this place was nearby!
من الجيّد أنّه كان يوجد مطعم جيّد بالقرب
I'm gonna call my mom real quick.
سأتّصل بأمّي سريعاً
Mister! Don't forget the rice!
!يا عمّ! لا تنسَ الأرز
You eat okonomiyaki with rice?
تأكل الأكونومياكي مع الأرزّ؟
Of course! It's a main dish!
هذا طبيعيّ، فالأكونومياكي طبق جانبيّ
Rice with the sauce on it is great, too!
!توجد صلصة على الأرزّ، وتجعل طعمه لذيذاً
Osaka's neat!
!أوساكا مثيرة للاهتمام حقّاً
Yeah!
بالفعل
Oh! That seat is taken--
...هذا المقعد محجو
You're Kudo, aren't you?
أنت كودو، أليس كذلك؟
Heiji's always talking about you.
يتكلّم هيجي عنك دوماً
Whoa, now!
!مهلك! مهلك
Hattori-kun does?!
هاتّوري-كن؟
Don't play dumb. I already know everything.
لا داعي للتظاهر بالحماقة، فأنا أعرف كلّ شيء
H-Hold on!
!لـ-لحظة
I know you're the Kudo broad from Tokyo who's seducing him!
...أنت
Umm, I think you have the wrong idea...
...المعذرة، أظنّكِ أسأتِ الفهم
I have just one thing to say to you:
سأخبرك بأمرٍ واحد
Heiji and I were once bound by "chains of iron"!
"أنا وهيجي مربوطان بـ "السلسة الحديديّة منذ وقتٍ طويل
If you want to mess with Heiji, you gotta go through me--!
!إذا أردتِ العبث مع هيجي، فعليكِ تجاوزي
Hey, Kazuha.
ماذا يا كازوها؟
What're you doing here?
ما الذي تفعلينه هنا؟
You're hilarious!
!يا لطرافتها
The "Kudo" I talked about is a guy! A guy!
كودو الذي كنت أتكلّم عنه !هو شاب! شاب
Toyama Kazuha (17) Heiji's childhood friend
(توياما كازوها (17 صديقة طفولة هيجي
And this girl is Kudo's squeeze.
وهذه الآنسة هي فتاة كودو
Squeeze?
فتاته؟
I-It isn't like that!
!لـ-ليس الأمر هكذا
She says she isn't.
إنّها تخالفك
She's just embarrassed.
لكنّها تحمرّ خجلاً
Then why didn't you ask Kudo to come too?
لمَ لم تستدعي كودو-كن ذاك إلى هنا أيضاً إذاً؟
Don't be stupid! Kudo's sitting right--!
...يا حمقاء! كودو موجـ
H-He couldn't make it!
!مـ-مشغول، فلم يستطع القدوم
Anyway, tell us more about this "chains of iron" thing!
عموماً، أخبرنا عن رابطة !تلك السلسلة الحديديّة
When we were kids, we found my old man's handcuffs in the attic.
...في صغرنا، وجدت في عليّة منزلي
Then we got stuck together when I pretended to be a policeman!
عندما قرّرنا لعب لعبة الشرطة، لم نستطع نزعها بعدها
It was lame; we found ourselves in big trouble!
ومررنا بوقتٍ عصيب، كان أمراً سخيفاً
It was not lame! We had to bathe and use the bathroom together!
!لم يكن سخيفاً
You moron! Don't tell them that!
!حمقاء! لا داعي لتخبريهم بذلك
Bathe and use the bathroom?
الاستحمام واستعمال المرحاض؟
Sounds like a smelly relationship.
أي أنّها علاقة منتنة
To commemorate it, I put a piece of the chain in here for good luck!
إحياءً للذكرى، أضفت قطعةً من تلك السلسلة في تميمة الحظّ هذه
Gross! Throw that thing away!
!مقرف! تخلّصي منها
Say! Are you two going out?!
أخبراني، أأنتما في علاقة عاطفيّة؟
No, no! Heiji and I are just childhood friends!
!كـ-كلا! أنا وهيجي مجرّد صديقا طفولة
I'm like his big sister who's always looking after him!
أنا أشبه بأخته الكبيرة التي تعتني به دوماً
Sure you are.
لا يحقّ لك قول ذلك
Her dad's chief detective of the Osaka police and my dad's friend,
،والدها كبير المحقّقين في شرطة أوساكا وهو صديق أبي
so we've known each other since we were kids, that's all.
،فكنّا نعرف بعضنا مُذ صغرنا هذا كلّ ما بالأمر
A detective runt and the daughter of a police detective...
...صبي متحرٍّ وابنة محقّق شرطة
What an ominous couple...
يا للثنائيّ المشؤوم
Eh? How come? What's wrong with that?
ماذا؟ لمَ؟ لا أرى مشكلة
Still, why are you here?
لكن لمَ أنتِ هنا؟
I was acting as your big sister and keeping watch
،بما أنّي أؤدي دور أختك الكبيرة كنت أقوم بمراقبتك
so the creepy Tokyo girl won't try and seduce you!
كيلا تغويك فتاة طوكيو الغريبة
Keeping watch? From where?
مراقبتي؟ من أين؟
The Tsutenkaku Tower.
برج تسوتينكاكو
Now I see! She was the one I sensed watching me!
فهمت
Thanks for the meal!
شكراً على الطعام
I'm stuffed!
أكلتُ كثيراً
That was delicious!
كان الطعام لذيذاً
Sorry to keep you waiting! You should've joined us!
،نعتذر على جعلك تنتظر !كان حريّ بك مشاركتنا
No, no, I'm just here to show you around!
لا داعي، دوري اصطحابكم فحسب
Where to next?
أين نذهب تالياً؟
I guess only Osaka Castle is left...
أرى أنّ أفضل مكان هي قلعة أوساكا
What are you doing in here?
لمَ صعدتِ؟
Oh, come on! Take me with you!
!أين المشكلة؟ اصطحبوني معكم
What a pain...
...يا إلهي
Huh?
ماذا هناك؟
What happened to this man?!
ما خطب هذا الرجل؟
I don't know! He suddenly fell onto the hood of the car!
لا أدري، سقط على غطاء السيّارة فجأةً
From the roof of this building!
من سطح هذا المبنى
Someone's up there!
!يوجد أحد هناك
Sakata-han! Contact the police!
!ساكاتا-هان! اتّصل بالشرطة
G-Got it!
حسناً
H-Hey!
!مهلك
Heiji!
!هيجي
Conan-kun!
!كونان-كن
Alright!
،حسناً
Now you tell us why you dropped that body on top of a police car!
أخبرنا لمَ أسقطت الجثّة على سيّارة شرطة؟
N-No! I'm just a--!
...كـ-كلا! أنا فقط
What?! He was called to the roof?!
ماذا؟ اُستدعي للسطح؟
Yeah... someone called this guy about a strange man on the roof.
أجل، تلقّى هذا الرجل اتّصالاً يفيد بوجود رجل غريب على السطح، فصعد هناك
I run a tea shop on the second floor, you see...
أنا أدير متجر شاي في الطابق الثاني لهذه البناية
But what sent the body falling?
لكن ما الذي أسقط الجثّة؟
The body was wrapped in rope, attached to the roof's handrail,
كانت الجثّة مربوطةً بحبل، ومعلّقةً بسور السطح المعدنيّ
and covered with a tarp, while the other end of the rope
ويغطّيها غطاء فينيليّ، بينما طرف الحبل الآخر
was tied to the door so the rope would come undone when opened.
رُبط بالباب بحيث ينحلّ عندما يفتحه أحد
I put his estimated time of death at about one full day ago.
وقت وفاته المقدّر هو قبل يومٍ كامل من الآن
So someone murdered him this time yesterday and left him hanging.
أي أنّ أحدهم قتله بالأمس قرابة هذا الوقت وجعله يتدلّى
But why on top of a police car?
لكن لمَ فوق سيّارة شرطة؟
It was probably just coincidence,
لعلّ سقوطه عليها كان محض مصادفة
but it could be someone trying to make an example...
أو ربما ضرب مثال من أحدهم
Example?
ضرب مثال؟
The knife through the wallet and heart...
...سكّين اخترقت المحفظة وطعنت صدره
This is clearly connected with those incidents...
هذا مرتبط بتلك القضيّة بوضوح
Hey! Lady! Hold up!
!لحظة، يا سيّدة
Hey! Wait!
!أنت
There she goes!
رحلت
It's all right. I got her license plate number.
لا بأس، حفظت رقم لوحتها
But never mind that. Tell me about "those incidents," Hattori!
ذلك جانباً، أخبرني عن تلك القضيّة التي ذكرتها يا هاتّوري
Tojiri Police Station, Osaka
مركز شرطة توجيري -  محافظة أوساكا
Serial murders?!
!سـ-سلسلة جرائم قتل؟
And that man who fell was the third one?!
!والرجل الذي سقط قبل قليل هو الضحيّة الثالثة؟
Yep.
أجل
In each case, they were stabbed in the chest, through their wallets.
في كلّ جريمة، طُعن الضحيّة في صدره عبر محفظته
After they were strangled to death with something.
بعدما قُتل خنقاً بشيءٍ ما
Maybe it was someone who held a grudge about money?
ألا يمكن أنّه شخص يكنّ ضغينةً بسبب المال؟
No, we can't say that for sure.
لا يمكننا الجزم بذلك
The first victim, Nagao Hidetoshi,
،كان الضحيّة الأولى، ناغاو هيديتوشي
Nagao Hidetoshi Convenience store owner
ناغاو هيديتوشي مالك متجر تموينات
The next victim, Nishiguchi Tayo,
،والضحيّة التالية، نيشيغوتشي تايو
Nishiguchi Tayo Pub mistress
نيشيغوتشي تايو مالكة حانة صغيرة
was the mistress of a small pub.
كانت مالكة حانة صغيرة
And the one who fell was Noyasu Kazuto,
نوياسو كازوتو سائق سيّارة أجرة
a taxi driver.
كان سائق سيّارة أجرة
None of them had enough money to incur someone's wrath.
لم يملك أيٌّ منهم مالاً يكفي ليثير ضغينة أحدهم
In fact, none of them are connected in any way.
كما لا تربطهم أيّ صلة حتّى الآن
There's no connection?
لا صلة؟
Nope.
أجل
They were all born, raised, schooled, and employed in Osaka,
كانت ولادتهم ونشأتهم ودراستهم كما نطاق عملهم في أوساكا
but all in different places.
لكن في أماكن متفرّقة
We found it, Heiji-kun! We found a link between the victims!
!وجدناها يا هيجي-كن! الصلة بين الضحايا
Seriously?!
!حقّاً؟
Goshi-san! Any comments?!
!غوشي-سان! ألديك أيّة تعليقات؟
Huh? Isn't this from Goshi Sotaro's corruption case six years ago?
ما هذا؟ أليست قضيّة محاكمة فساد عضو مجلس النوّاب غوشي سوتارو قبل 6 أعوام؟
The case where his secretary took responsibility for him and quit?
القضيّة التي تحمّل فيها المساعد كامل المسؤولية واستقال من عمله؟
As I recall, the secretary's name was Nagao...
...وفقما أذكر، كان اسم المساعد ناغاو
Hey! Is our Nagao--?!
...لحظة، أيمكن أنّ ناغاو
Yes.
أجل
Nagao Hidetoshi, the first one who was killed!
كان هذا الرجل الضحيّة الأولى، ناغاو هيديتوشي
But didn't you already investigate this? Why now?
لكن ألم تتفقّد ذلك سلفاً؟ لمَ تذكره مجدداً؟
No, take a look at the driver.
كلا، ما أريدك منك النظر إليه هو السائق
The driver?
السائق؟
Th-That's Noyasu, the third victim!
!هـ-هذا نوياسو، الضحيّة الثالثة
It seems he was Assemblyman Goshi's driver until four years ago.
كان سائق عضو مجلس النوّاب غوشي حتّى قبل أربعة وفقما يبدو
His former secretary and his former driver...
...مساعده السابق وسائقه الشخصيّ السابق
Assemblyman Goshi may be involved in this.
قد يكون هذا مرتبطاً بعضو مجلس النوّاب غوشي
We thought so too, so one of my seniors is headed to his place now.
فكرنا بذلك، لذا يتّجه أحد زملائي الأكبر خبرة إلى منزله الآن
Still, he's famous for his hatred of police.
لكنّ غوشي مشهور بكرهه للشرطة
Just going to see him won't help anything.
قد يتطلّب مجرّد لقائه عناءً
Then what do you say we pay a visit too, Sakata-chan?
ما رأيك بأن نذهب له بدورنا يا ساكاتا-هان؟
Hold on! You should leave that to the police!
!مهلك! عليك ترك ذلك للشرطة
Don't be stupid.
أحمق
I can't just let the guy who screwed up your Osaka tour get away!
لا أستطيع ترك الشخص الذي أفسد جولتكم في أوساكا يعبث طليقاً
Head over to my house! Kazuha can tell you where it is!
خذوا عنوان منزلي من كازوها واسبقوني إلى هناك
Heiji! Do you have the good luck charm?!
هيجي! هل تميمة الحظّ معك؟
Yep, sure do. Don't worry.
أجل، إنّها معي، لا تقلقي
Well, later!
أراكم لاحقاً
What good luck charm?
أيّ تميمة حظّ؟
A good luck charm I gave him. It's always protected his life.
تميمةٌ أعطيته إيّاها، لطالما حمت حياته
What nonsense.
مبالغة
It's true!
!إنّها الحقيقة
The last time he forgot it, he got really hurt in a kendo match!
،في المرّة الفائتة التي نسيها فيه تأذّى بشدّة في مباراة كيندو
They're very important charms! There are only two in the world!
إنّها تميمةٌ هامّة جدّاً لا يوجد منها إلّا اثنتان في هذا العالم
Two?
اثنتان؟
Yeah, remember that story about us and the handcuffs?
ألم أخبركم قبل قليل عن قصّة الأصفاد التي ربطتني وهيجي في الماضي؟
I secretly put a piece of the chain in his good luck charm!
أضفت قطعةً منها في تميمة هيجي سرّاً أيضاً
Oh?
هكذا إذاً
Though it's none of your business!
رغم أنّ الأمر لا يخصّك
Y-Yeah.
صـ-صحيح
Never mind that. I don't see the runt anywhere...
ذلك جانباً، لا أرى ذاك الصبيّ
Eh?!
ماذا؟
Did he go to the bathroom?
لعلّه ذهب للحمّام
I guess this means no more police cars...
لا نستطيع الذهاب بسيّارة شرطة إذاً
Sorry, Sakata-chan.
آسفٌ يا ساكاتا-هان
You gotta write a letter apologizing for the crushed car, don't you?
كان عليك كتابة تقرير عن أضرار تحطّم السيّارة، أليس كذلك؟
It's fine. I'm used to it.
ليست مشكلة، فأنا معتاد
But what's with the gut?
ذلك جانباً، لمَ معدتك هكذا؟
Oh, this?
هذا؟
This kid'll be helpful!
سيفيدنا هذا الصبيّ
But won't Mori-han be worried?!
لكن ألن يكون موري-هان قلقاً؟
It's okay! I'll call him later!
ليست مشكلة، سأتّصل به لاحقاً
Oh, that reminds me, we used the license plate number to get
بالمناسبة، وجدنا عنوان ورقم هاتف المرأة المشبوهة التي رأيتَها
the address and phone number of that suspicious woman you saw.
عبر رقم لوحة سيّارتها
Her name is Okazaki Sumie, age 39.
اسمها أوكازاكي سومي، 39 عاماً
She divorced last year and lives alone in the West Side Apartments.
تطلّقت العام الفائت، وتعيش في مجمع شقق الجانب الغربيّ بالقرب من هنا
Want to check her out first?
أتريد المرور بها أوّلاً؟
Yeah... it seemed like she knew something.
حسناً، بدا أنّها تعرف شيئاً
Here, I'll call to see if she's home or not.
سأجرّب الاتّصال بها لرؤية ما إن كانت في المنزل
West Side Apartments
مجمع شقق الجانب الغربيّ
At 1:00 pm today, a body fell near the Shinsai Bridge.
،في الواحدة من ظهر اليوم سقطت جثّة بجوار جسر شينساي
The deceased was identified as Noyasu Kazuto-san, age 41.
تم التعرّف على هويّة المتوفّى، وتبيّن أنّه نوياسو كازوتو-سان، 41 عاماً
Moreover...
...إضافةً لذلك
Forgive me... Forgive me...
...سامحني... سامحني
Yes?
أجل؟
Oh, is this Okazaki-san's residence?
أهذا منزل أوكازاكي-سان؟
My name is Sakata, I'm with the Tojiri Police Department.
،أنا ساكاتا، من شرطة محافظة أوساكا مركز توجيري
O-Officer! Hurry here and protect me! I'm going to be killed!
حـ-حضرة الضابط! تعال إلى هنا سريعاً !واحمني! سوف أُقتل
I'll tell you everything! Just hurry here! Hurry!
،سأكشف لكم كلّ ما حدث بالماضي !لذا أسرعوا إلى هنا! بسرعة
Just calm down! I'll be right there!
اهدئي بأيّ حال، سنأتي فوراً
Lock your door and don't let anyone in!
!أقفلي أبوابك، ولا تسمحي لأحد بالدخول
Oh no! We passed the West Side Apartments!
!كلا! تجاوزنا مجمع الشقق الغربيّ
What now?! It's a one-way road and it's a heavy traffic day!
،ماذا نفعل؟! اليوم موعد تسليم أجور فشارع ميدوسوجي مزدحم
It'll take forever to turn around!
سنحتاج وقتاً طويلاً للاستدارة
It'll be faster on foot! Stop the car!
!سيكون الركض أسرع! توقّف قليلاً
H-Heiji-kun!
!هـ-هيجي-كن؟
Watch it!
!انتبه
Sorry!
!آسف
West Side Apartments
مجمع شقق الجانب الغربيّ
Hey! Lady! We're with that cop who called earlier! Open up!
أنت! يا سيّدة! نحن مع الشرطّي الذي !اتّصلتِ به قبل قليل، افتحي الباب
It's unlocked!
غير مقفل
Hey! Lady!
أنت، يا سيّدة؟
Hey!
!أنت
Lady! Where are you?!
يا سيّدة! أين أنت؟
This is Sakata.
أجل، معك ساكاتا
Eh?! Okazaki-san isn't home?!
!ماذا؟ أوكازاكي-سان ليست في البيت؟
Nope. The place is empty.
أجل، إنّه فارغ
That's crazy! I told her not to leave!
!هذه حماقة! أخبرتها ألّا تغادر
Did she contact you at all?
هل وردك اتّصال منها؟
Of course not. I didn't give her my number.
بالطبع لا، فلم أعطها رقمي
Oh, right.
ذلك صحيح
Anyway, hurry here. Something's not right.
.أيّاً يكن، تعال هنا بسرعة هناك أمرٌ غريب
I just got off the one-way road, so I'll be there in a few minutes.
،خرجت من ميدوسوجي للتوّ سأصلكم في 3 إلى 4 دقائق
It's from downstairs!
!إنّه من الأسفل
The public restroom!
الحمّام العمومي؟
D-Don't tell me she--!
...أ-أيمكن
Too late. She's dead.
فات الأوان، إنّها ميتة
But why?! Why did she go outside?!
لكن لمَ. لمَ غادرت المنزل؟
And there's a knife through her wallet and chest...
...وطُعنت بسكّين في صدرها عبر محفظتها
Who's doing this?! And why?!
من فعل هذا؟ ولمَ؟
The victim is Okazaki Sumie-san, age 39.
الضحيّة هي أوكازاكي سومي-سان، 39 عاماً
She was strangled to death with a rope of some sort.
سبب الموت كان الخنق بحبلٍ ما
She appears to have been stabbed after being strangled.
يبدو أنّها طُعنت بالسكّين بعدما خُنقت
What time did you find the body?
متى وجدت الجثّة؟
Three or four minutes before you arrived.
قبل 3 إلى 4 دقائق قبيل قدومك
This bathroom cleaner guy found her.
وجدها منظّف دورة المياه هذا
But why does the killer stab their wallets every time?
لكن لمَ يطعن القاتل المحفظة كلّ مرّة؟
You told this lady not to go outside, but it looks like she died here.
،أخبرتَ هذه السيّدة بألّا تخرج لكن يبدو أنّها ماتت هنا
Come to the Shinsai Bridge now if you want to see some old friends.
،تعالي إلى جسر شينساي الآن ستلتقين صديقاً قديماً
1:08 pm.
الواحدة وثمان دقائق مساءً
See that? You're the next to wind up like that.
رأيتِ؟ أنتِ التالية التي ستلقى هذا المصير
1:10 pm.
الواحدة وعشر دقائق مساءً
There's no question that's the killer!
لا شكّ أنّ هذه رسائل من القاتل
In other words, the lady heard the first message
مما يعني أنّ تلك السيّدة سمعت الرسالة الأولى
and went to the Shinsai Bridge.
وذهبت لجسر شينساي
Then, when she came back, she heard the second message
ثمّ عندما رجعت، سمعت الرسالة الثانية
and trembled in fear inside.
وبقيت مرتعدةً في شقّتها
But what does "old friends" mean?
لكن ما قصده بالصديق القديم؟
Could it refer to the people who've been killed so far?
لعلّه يشير للأشخاص الذين قتلهم حتّى الآن
Detective Sakata. There's a call from headquarters.
محقّق ساكاتا، هنالك اتّصال من مقرّ القيادة
Hey, Hattori. These answering machine messages are strange.
هاتّوري، رسائل آلة الردّ هذه غريبة
How so?
كيف ذلك؟
The times and the contents of the messages.
وقت ومحتوى الرسائل
There were only two minutes between the "come" message
تفصل دقيقتان فحسب بين رسالة "تعالي" الأولى
and the "see that" message.
ورسالة "رأيتِ" الثانية
Does that mean the killer was watching her?
أيعني هذا أنّ القاتل كان يراقبها؟
Something's odd about these four murders.
هنالك أمرٌ غريب في سلسلة جرائم القتل الأربع هذه
I get a bad feeling that the killer is playing with us...
يراودني شعورٌ سيّئ بتلاعب القاتل بنا
Bad feeling?
شعور سيّئ؟
Kudo!
!كودو
What?!
ما الأمر؟
N-Nothing! Don't sweat it!
!لا-لا شيء! لا تهتم
Yikes! I just remembered that ominous dream from the other day!
كلا، تذكّرت ذاك الحلم المشؤوم
So, Heiji-kun. Where to next?
إذاً هيجي-كن، أين نذهب تالياً؟
Shall we visit Goshi-san's office?
هل نتوجّه لمكتب غوشي-سان؟
Heiji-kun?
هيجي-كن؟
Oh, right.
...صحيح
These sure are strange cases.
لكن هذه قضايا غريبة بحقّ
There are no witnesses and it's not clear how they're all connected,
لا شهود عيان، ولا نعرف العلاقة بينها
yet we can ID the victims easily enough.
مع ذلك نستطيع اكتشاف هويّات الضحايا فوراً
Yeah, now that you mention it.
معك حقّ
The victims' names were on the news right after the first two killings.
أُذيع اسم أوّل ضحيّتين في الأنباء فور اكتشاف الجثّتين
That's only natural.
ذلك طبيعيّ
All four had their driver's licenses in their stabbed wallets.
فقد كانت رخص قيادتهم موجودة في المحافظ المطعونة بالسكّين
Driver's licenses? That's it!
!رخص قيادتهم؟ هذه هي
Kadoma Driver's License Testing Ground
ساحة اختبار كادوما لرخص القيادة
So all four have clean driving records...
لم تكن هنالك حوادث أو مخالفات في سجّلات الأربعة المرورية إذاً؟
Yes.
أجل
I thought there might be a car connection. Guess I was wrong again.
،ظننتُ أنّنا قد نجد صلة بالسيّارات لكن يبدو أنّ تخميني لم يصب
They also all got their licenses different years at different places.
إضافةً لذلك، أمكنة وتواريخ إصدار رخص قيادة الأربعة مختلفة
Hey... it says Okazaki learned to drive in Hyogo and not Osaka.
اسمع، مكتوبٌ أنّ أوكازاكي-سان وحدها تعلّمت القيادة في هيوغو وليس أوساكا
So it does.
بالفعل
Why that far away?
لمَ فعلت هناك؟
License school?! Does that mean--?!
...مخيّم تمرين؟! أيمكن
...If you want to see some old friends.
ستلتقين صديقاً قديماً
There's her friends!
إنّهما صديقان
Do you have the number for that place, Mister?
أتعرف رقم هاتف ذاك المكان يا سيّد؟
Yes.
أجل
Okazaki Sumie and Nishiguchi Tayo shared a room at the school?!
تشاركت أوكازاكي سومي ونيشيغوتشي تايو غرفةً أثناء المخيم؟
Seriously?!
حـ-حقّاً؟
Alright! We're starting to connect the four victims now!
!حسناً! بدأنا نجد روابط بين الضحايا الأربعة
But... isn't it strange?
لكن... أليس هذا غريباً؟
Okazaki-san got her license that same year,
حصلت أوكازاكي-سان على رخصتها ،في ذاك العام
but Nishiguchi-san got his three years later.
لكن حاول نيشيغوتشي-سان الحصول على رخصته مجدداً بعد ثلاثة أعوام
Maybe he sucked at driving and didn't graduate that year?
لعلّه كان فاشلاً في القيادة، ولم يتخرّج ذاك العام؟
That's crazy!
!لا-لا يمكن
You're really sure about that?!
!أأنت متأكّد؟
Huh?! What is it?!
ماذا؟ ما الأمر؟
The others were at that school twenty years ago, too!
كان هنالك آخرون بالإضافة لـ أوكازاكي-سان ونيشيغوتشي-سان في ذاك المخيم قبل 20 عاماً
The first victim, Nagao Hidetoshi-san,
الضحيّة الأولى ناغاو هيديتوشي-سان
the third victim, Noyasu Kazuto-san,
والضحيّة الثالثة نوياسو كازوتو-سان
and Assemblyman Goshi-san!
!كما عضو مجلس النوّاب غوشي-سان، هؤلاء الثلاثة
They were all at the same place!
!ارتادوا جميعاً المكان نفسه
What?!
!ماذا؟
And that's not all.
ليس هذا كلّ شيء
There was also a man whose name is all too familiar now.
كان هنالك رجلٌ معروف الاسم في ذاك المخيّم أيضاً
Familiar?! Who?!
معروف؟ من هو؟
Numabuchi. Numabuchi Kiichiro.
نو-نومابوتشي، نومابوتشي كيتشيرو
Numabuchi Kiichiro? You don't mean--!
...نومابوتشي كيتشيرو؟ أيمكن
The robber and murderer...
...المجرم الهارب حالياً
...who's on the run?!
مرتكب السطو والقتل؟
Here it comes! The school photo!
ها هي، مدرسة المخيّم
No question about it! It's Numabuchi!
لا شكّ في الأمر، إنّه نومابوتشي
The faces and names of the other five match, too!
أوجه وأسماء الخمسة الآخرين متطابقة أيضاً
But this is strange!
لكن هذا غريب
August 23, 1978 graduates
خرّيجو 23 أغسطس، 1978
See? It says they all graduated then...
أترى؟ مكتوبٌ أنّهم تخرّجوا بعد المخيّم
...but only Okazaki-san went on to get her license.
لكن كانت أوكازاكي-سان وحدها من حصلت على الرخصة
Something happened at this school twenty years ago. Something...
حصل أمرٌ ما في ذاك المخيّم قبل 20 عاماً، أمرٌ ما
I see. Thanks.
هكذا إذاً، شكراً
None of the current staff know anything that happened twenty years ago.
لا يعرف أحد العاملين الحاليين شيئاً عمَ حصل قبل 20 عاماً
I figured as much.
لا عجب
But there had to have been some sort of incident
لكن لا بدّ من وجود حادثة
Prefectural Nakanoshima Library
مكتبة ناكانوشيما الإقليمية
involving that training ground twenty years ago.
وقعت في ساحة التمرين تلك قبل 20 عاماً
Bingo! This is it!
!ها هي! هذه
Driving Instructor Dies in Accident Drunk Driving Suspected
موت معلّم قيادة في حادث اشتباه بقيادته ثملاً
On that day twenty years ago when those six graduated,
،في يوم تخرّج أولئك الستّة قبل 20 عاماً
one of the instructors died in a drunk driving accident!
كان أحد المعلّمين يقود ثملاً، ولقي حتفه
His name was Inaba Tetsuji. The strictest instructor at the school...
اسمه إينابا تيتسوجي، أكثر المعلّمين صرامة في المدرسة
Hey, how does this sound to you?
اسمع، ما رأيك بهذا؟
Numabuchi, broke and in trouble, decided to use the old incident
قرّر نومابوتشي الواقع في مشكلة ماليّة بعدما نفدّت مدّخرات هروبه
to blackmail the assemblyman out of money but was refused.
ابتزاز عضو مجلس النوّاب غوشي بالحادثة القديمة للحصول على المال، لكنّه قُوبل بالرفض
So he killed off everyone involved in the incident
فقتل رفاقه القدامى ذوي الصلة بالحادثة واحداً تلو الآخر
and then repeated his threat.
وكرّر تهديده
That, or Goshi used Numabuchi to kill off everyone
أو ربما استعمل غوشي نومابوتشي لقتل الجميع
to keep the scandal from interfering with his Diet member campaign.
كيلا تعكّر الضحيّة القدمة حملة ترشّحه للبرلمان
Both sound plausible enough.
كلاهما أمران محتملان
When Nagao-san and Noyasu-san quit working for him,
عندما توقّف ناغاو-سان ونوياسو-سان عن عمليهما ،كمساعد وسائق شخصيّ له
they received a lot of severance pay.
تلقّيا أجر إنهاء خدمة مُجزٍ وفقما يبدو
Mention the instructor's death and his companions back then,
عندما نذكر حادثة معلّمه قبل 20 عاماً ،وأسماء رفاقه في المخيّم
and I bet that cop-hater will start talking!
فلا بدّ أن حتّى كاره الشرطة ذاك سيفتح فمه
Okay! Let's go!
هيّا، لنذهب
Conan-kun! What are you doing here?! You suddenly disappeared!
كونان-كن! ما الذي تفعله في مكانٍ كهذا؟
Oh no! I forgot to call!
!تبّاً! نسيت الاتّصال
Hey, Hei-chan! Long time, no see!
مرحباً يا هي-تشان، مضى وقتٌ طويل
Otaki-han from headquarters?! Why are you here?!
أوتاكي-هان من مقرّ القيادة أيضاً؟ لمَ أنت هنا؟
Kazuha-chan asked me to be a driver.
طلبت منّي كازوها-تشان أن أكون السائق
Inspector Otaki Osaka Prefectural Police
المفتّش أوتاكي مقرّ قيادة شرطة محافظة أوساكا
Sakata-han called us about the glasses boy.
اتّصل بنا ساكاتا-سان، وأتينا لأخذ الصبيّ ذو النظّارات
Now why'd you do that?
بأيّ حاجة؟
Must be convenient, always having the cops at your beck and call!
تتأمّرين رجال الشرطة كما تشائين
Who're you to talk?! You were touring Osaka in a police car!
استعملتَ سيّارة شرطة لأخذ جولة !في أوساكا، فلا يحقّ لك الكلام
Now, now!
هوّنا عليكما
I can drive the boy to the chief's house if you'd like.
سأقلّ هذا الطفل إلى منزل الرئيس إذا أردتم
Shall we go?
هل نذهب يا ولد؟
No! I wanna stay with Heiji-niichan!
!كلا! أريد البقاء مع هيجي-نيتشان
Just a minute, Otaki-han.
انتظر قليلاً يا أوتاكي-هان
This is Osaka. Just leave this to us and go on your way, Kudo!
هذه أوساكا، دع القضيّة لنا وانسحب يا كودو
But knowing you, you'll just find a way to butt in again.
لكن بمعرفتي بك، ستجد طريقةً لإقحام أنفك بالتأكيد
Fine, then. I'll let you hold onto this.
ليس بيدي حيلة، سأتركك تحتفظ بهذه
Your good luck charm?
التميمة؟
In exchange, hold yourself back as much as you can today.
في المقابل، اضبط نفسك قدر المستطاع اليوم
When I come home, I'll tell you all about what happened!
عندما أرجع للبيت، سأحكي لك كلّ تفاصيل القضيّة
'Kay?
اتّفقنا؟
Conan-kun! Hurry up!
كونان-كن، اصعد بسرعة
Don't worry. I won't let them mess with Osaka anymore!
لا تقلق، لن أدعه يعبث بأوساكا أكثر مما فعل
I bet my life on it!
أراهن بحياتي على هذا
See you later!
!أراكم لاحقاً
Who's he talking to?
من كان يكلّمه؟
I'm starving...
أشعر بالجوع
We'll be at the chief's house in Neyagawa in half an hour...
سنصل لمنزل الرئيس في نيياغاوا في غضون نصف ساعة
Heiji's mom is making blowfish stew tonight!
قالت أمّ هيجي أنّها ستعدّ حساء السمكة المنتفخة للعشاء
Oh?!
حقّاً؟
I can't wait!
أتطلّع لذلك
Otaki.
أجل، معك أوتاكي
What?!
!ماذا؟
You found the car of Numabuchi, the fugitive,
وجدتم سيّارة نومابوتشي الهارب
in the Mino mountains?!
!في جبال مينو؟
I'll be right there!
!حسناً، سآتي فوراً
Sorry, Mori-han, but you'll have to wait longer for the blowfish stew.
موري-هان، أنا آسف، لكن عليك تأجيل حساء السمكة المنتفخة قليلاً
I'm taking a side trip!
!سآخذ منعطفاً
Mino Waterfall
شلّال مينو
Sorry! I'll have a youngster come get you in a minute.
آسف، سأجعل ضابطاً يافعاً يقلّكم في لحظات
Okay...
حسناً
Isn't Numabuchi that murderer who escaped with a gun?
أليس نومابوتشي هو القاتل الذي هرب ومعه مسدّس؟
Things have gotten really bad. Right, Conan--?
...أصبح الوضع سيّئاً، أليس كذلك يا كونان
Conan-kun!
!كونان-كن
How's it look?
كيف الأمر؟
Oh, Inspector Otaki!
مفتّش أوتاكي
We found the car covered in plants, but Numabuchi is still...
،وجدنا السيّارة والحشائش تغطّيها لكن لم نجد نومابوتشي بعد
And that shack?
وذاك الكوخ؟
It was empty when I peeked inside.
لم نجد فيه أحداً عندما تفقّدنا قبل قليل
Maybe he ditched the car and ran off somewhere else?
لعلّه ترك السيّارة وهرب إلى مكانٍ آخر
He's in there.
إنّه موجود في الداخل
L-Little boy! When did you get here?!
!يا-يا فتى! متى وصلت هنا؟
Have a look here!
انظروا هنا
I found these burned at the bottom of this can.
وجدتُ هذه الآثار المحترقة مدفونةً تحت العشب في هذه الحاوية
See? Convenience store receipts from five and three days ago,
أترون؟ إنّها إيصالات متجر تموينات ترجع لقبل خمسة وثلاثة أيام
and stickers from lots of convenience store lunches that expire today.
كما ملصقات ختم علب غداء من متاجر تموينات تاريخ انتهائها اليوم
Not many people would eat convenience store lunches
لا يأكل الكثيرون علب غداء المتاجر
at a place like this every day, right?
في مكانٍ كهذا يومياً، أليس كذلك؟
But, boy, if a wanted man showed up at a convenience store...
لكن يا فتى، إذا ظهر رجل مطلوبٌ ...للعدالة في متجر تموينات
Someone else probably bought it.
من اشتراها كان شخصاً آخراً على الأرجح
Someone's sheltering him.
أحدهم يؤيه
For some reason...
لسببٍ ما
Hey! You find Numabuchi?!
إذاً، أوجدت نومابوتشي؟
Well?!
كيف الأمر؟
No! There are signs that someone lived here awhile ago, but...
...كلا، هنالك آثار لعيش أحدٍ هنا قبل فترة، لكن
There's mud on the windowsill!
هنالك وحلٌ على عتبة النافذة
That pillar and those beams are free of cobwebs...
لا خيوط عناكب على العامود والعارضة هناك
I see! He stood on the windowsill and...
...فهمت، وقف على عتبة النافذة
S-Stop, little boy!
!أ-أنت، يا فتى
Oh?! It looks like this leads to the attic!
ماذا؟ يبدو أنه يمكنك الذهاب للعليّة من هنا
Wait, boy! Leave the rest to us!
!انتظر يا فتى! دع الباقي لنا
Numabuchi!
!نومابوتشي
Numabuchi Kiichiro! You're under arrest for robbery and murder!
نومابوتشي كيتشيرو! أنت تحت الاعتقال !لجريمة السطو والقتل
F-Food!
!الـ-الطعام
Hurry, give me food!
!بسرعة، أعطوني طعاماً
Goshi Sotaro's residence
منزل غوشي سوتارو
What?! Old man Goshi won't come out?!
ماذا؟ المُسنّ غوشي لم يخرج؟
No, he's kept us waiting in here since this evening.
أجل، جعلنا ننتظره في هذه الغرفة منذ المساء
I'll go see him myself!
!سأذهب لمقابلته بنفسي
Now, now! Please simmer down and let my senior save face!
مهلك، لنبق هادئين ونترك زميلي الخبير يحفظ ماء وجهه
Sir! We can't keep the police detectives waiting any longer!
سينسي، لا يمكننا ترك رجال الشرطة ينتظرون أكثر
Goshi Sotaro Prefectural Assemblyman
غوشي سوتارو عضو في مجلس نوّاب المحافظة
Forget 'em. They'll give up and leave eventually.
دعهم وشأنهم، سيستلمون بنهاية المطاف ويرحلون
Shall I at least tell them about the phone call with the strange voice?
هل أعلمهم باتّصال الشخص غريب الصوت الذي وردنا قبل قليل على الأقل؟
N-No! I absolutely can't...
...كـ-كلا! لا يمكننا قطعاً
Let's make a deal in one hour about the incident twenty years ago.
لنعقد صفقةٌ حيال الحادثة قبل 20 عاماً بعد ساعة من الآن
Go out the back gate and wait in the far storehouse.
افتح الباب الخلفيّ وانتظر في المستودع البعيد بمفردك
We absolutely can't tell them!
لا يمكننا إخبارهم قطعاً
Sheesh! I told you to stop scampering around, Conan-kun!
يا إلهي، أخبرتك عن تتوقّف عن التجوّل يا كونان-كن
All you do is worry me...
كلّ ما تفعله هو جعلي أقلق
Sorry.
آسف
Come on! Get walking!
هيّا، امش بسرعة
Hey!
!أنت
Hey, you alright?
أأنت بخير؟
Outta the way!
!ابتعدا
It's no use!
!نومابوتشي
Conan-kun!
!كونان-كن
Conan-kun! Hang in there!
!كونان-كن! تماسك
It can't be--!
...لا يمكن
What is it, Heiji-kun?
ما الأمر يا هيجي-كن؟
Oh, nothing!
!لا شيء
Huh? Where's Sakata-han?
ماذا؟ أين ساكاتا-هان؟
He just left to use the bathroom.
غادر قبل قليل إلى دورة المياه
I should probably go, too.
لعلّي سأذهب بدوري
Conan-kun! Conan-kun!
!كونان-كن! كونان-كن
Someone rush him to the hospital!
!ليقلّه أحدكم للمشفى بشكلٍ عاجل
Yes, sir!
!حاضر
I'm okay... It only pricked me!
لا بأس، وخزتني فحسب
That can't be! The knife went--!
...أنت تكذب! فالسكّين قد
A good luck charm?
تميمة؟
Heiji's?
هيجي؟
See? The knife got caught in the chain link, so it couldn't stab me!
أترون؟ علقت مقدّمة السكين في حلقة رابطة السلسلة، فلم تطعنّي
Never do that again!
لا تتهوّر مُجدداً
Up, you!
!هيّا، انهض
No funny business!
!لا تتباطأ
Why does he have two handcuffs on his left hand?
لمَ على يده اليسرى صفدين؟
Oh, this? I'm not sure why, but he was handcuffed to a pillar.
هذا؟ لا أدري لمَ، لكنّه كان مقيّداً بعامود
We had to get him free, so we cut the chain and put our cuffs on him.
لم يكن أمامي خيار آخر، فقطعت تلك السلسلة وقيّدته بأصفادي
He was handcuffed?!
كان مقيّداً؟
Looks like you were right about someone bringing him food, kid.
يبدو أنّ أحدهم كان يجلب له الطعام كما قلت
Wait a minute!
!انتظر
It couldn't be! It couldn't be!
أيمكن؟ أيمكن؟
It couldn't be!
أيمكن؟
Oh no!
!كلا
Wait all you want, old man Goshi won't come.
انتظر قدرما تشاء، لن يأتي المُسنّ غوشي
Sakata-han. You're the serial murderer, aren't you?!
ساكاتا-هان، ألستَ المجرم وراء سلسلة جرائم القتل؟
P-Please don't joke like that!
!لا-لا تتفوّه بالهراء رجاءً
I was just admiring how unusual this storehouse is!
لفتت انتباهي غرابة هذا المستودع لا أكثر، فكنت أتأمّله
First, when the body fell onto the cop car...
بدايةً، الحادثة عندما سقطت ...الجثّة على سيّارة الشرطة
You craftily took us there.
حيث أخذتنا لذاك المكان بدهاء
Mere moments before we exited the restaurant, you made a call
قبل لحظات من مغادرتنا للمطعم، أجريتَ اتّصالاً
and put the special set-up in action.
...وفعّلت الآليّة التي ستجعل
Then, while I was on the roof, you called Okazaki-san to the scene,
بعدها، اتّصلتَ بأوكازاكي-سان عندما كنتُ على السطح، واستدعيتَها هنا
left a threatening call on her machine when you knew she was gone,
تركت رسالة تهديد على آلة ردّها بينما تعلم أنّها ليست في المنزل
and led her to hole up in her apartment.
وجعلتها تحتجز نفسها في شقّتها عند عودتها
After you had me witness her and made an impression on her,
بعدما جعلتني أشاهدها في مسرح الحادثة حيث تركت لديّ انطباعاً
you brought up the topic and called her after passing her apartment.
ذكرتَ موضوعها بعدما تجاوزنا مجمع شققها
Then, after I heard her frightened voice and leapt from the car,
،وبعدما سمعتُ صوتها الفزع ووثبت من السيّارة
you parked the car in an alley and called her again while chasing me.
،ركنت السيّارة في شارع جانبيّ فوراً وعاودت الاتّصال بها وأنت تلاحقني
I'm the detective who just called! You're in danger there!
!أنا المحقّق الذي اتّصل قبل قليل! مكانكِ خطر
Please wait in the nearby public restroom! Got it?!
فلتنتظري في دورة المياه العمومية المجاورة، حسناً؟
And then, while we were in her room, you killed her in the restroom!
...ثمّ، بينما كنّا في شقّتها
You were able to arrive by car immediately after she was found
بقتلها
because you had rented two cars of the exact same model!
هو لاستئجارك لسيّارتين من الطراز والتصميم الداخليّ نفسه
After you killed her, you got in the other rental car that was nearby
بعد قتلك لها، صعدت السيّارة المستأجرة الأخرى التي كانت بجوار البناية
to make it look like you'd just gotten there after some time.
كي يبدو أنّه تعيّن عليك أخذ منعطف بما أنّ ميدوسوجي طريق أحاديّ الاتّجاه، ولا تستطيع الذهاب شمالاً
You drove for us and got us closer to the heart of the case
إقلالك لي، كما إقرابي من جوهر القضيّة
to get everyone here so you could kill old man Goshi!
!كان كي تجمعنا هنا، وتقتل المُسنّ غوشي
He's a prefectural assemblyman. He'd stand out if he left his home.
،إنّه عضو في مجلس نوّاب المحافظة سيلفت الأنظار إذا غادر منزله
And he could even take bodyguards with him.
وقد يصطحب معه حرّاس شخصيّين إذا لم تكن حذراً
But if you came here with us, you could wander around freely.
لكن بقدومك هنا معي، يمكنك التجوّل في المنزل دون إثارة الريبة
When did you realize it, Heiji-kun?
متى أدركت يا هيجي-كن؟
The rental cars' side-view mirrors were the first thing.
كانت مرآة السيّارة المستأجرة الجانبيّة هي أوّل علامة
It was at a different angle the second time.
كانت زاويتها مختلفة عندما صعدتُ المرّة الثانية
And then I noticed the instructor in the picture from twenty years ago
ثمّ أدركت عندما دقّقت في الصورة التي وصلت بالفاكس
looked a lot like you.
قبل 20 عاماً
It was your habit in the car that finally convinced me.
كان عادتك عند صعودك السيّارة هي ما قطعت شكّي باليقين
You fiddled with the rear-view mirror
عدّلت مرآة الرؤية الخلفيّة
the same way Noyasu-san and Okazaki-san did!
بنفس أسلوب نوياسو-سان وأوكازاكي-سان
That's proof you'd all been involved with the same person.
هذا دليلٌ على أنّكم مرتبطون بالشخص نفسه
I don't know what happened twenty years ago,
،لا أعرف ما الذي حصل 20 عاماً
but shouldn't you turn yourself in, Sakata-han?
لكن ألا يجدر بك تسليم نفسك يا ساكاتا-هان؟
I'm sorry, Heiji-kun.
آسفٌ يا هيجي-كن
It's all over at this point...
انتهى الأمر في هذه المرحلة
You idiot!
!يا-يا أحمق
Sakata is the killer?!
!ساكاتا هو القاتل؟
That's right! Numabuchi told us everything!
أجل، أخبرنا نومابوتشي بكلّ شيء
After he committed the murders, he planned to frame Numabuchi
،بعد تنفيذ ساكاتا لسلسلة جرائم القتل كان ينوى إلفاق التهمة بـ نومابوتشي
and then kill him in a fake suicide!
ثمّ يقتله بحيث يبدو انتحاراً
Where's Sakata?!
!أين ساكاتا؟
H-He's been gone awhile--
...إ-إنّه غير موجود لفترة
There, it's empty! Now you can't do anything stupid!
هذه الرصاصات كلّها! لا يمكنك !الإقدام على حماقات الآن
A bullet hit your leg?!
هل أصابت طلقةٌ ساقك؟
N-Never mind me, Heiji-kun... Hurry and escape!
لا-لا تهتم لي، أسرع واهرب يا هيجي-كن
No can do... Looks like I got hit, too...
كلا... يبدو أنّي أُصبت في معدتي أيضاً
He was my father... The instructor who died twenty years ago.
كان أبي
He was a strict driver
كان سائقاً صارماً
and was always telling my mother to check the rear-view mirror.
ويخبر أمّي بالتحقّق من مرآة الرؤية الخلفيّة دوماً
That's probably where I got it from.
لا بدّ أنّ ذلك مصدر عادتي
Do you think someone like that would drive drunk?!
أتظنّ شخصاً مثله سيقود ثملاً؟
And then I became a police detective...
...لذا أصبحت محقّقاً في الشرطة
...to expose the truth of my father's death!
كي أكشف حقيقة موت أبي
I solved the mystery when I found Numabuchi in a mountain shack.
حللتُ اللغز عندما وجدت نومابوتشي الذي كان هارباً في كوخٍ جبليّ
I look like my father, so the instant he saw me, he grew frightened
ملامحي شبيهة أبي، فهلع عندما رآني
and blurted everything out.
ونطق بكلّ شيء
F-Forgive me, Instructor Inaba! It was just a prank!
!سامحني رجاءً يا معلّم إينابا! كان مجرّد مقلب
We just wanted to see your scared face
أردنا رؤية ملامح الخوف على معلّمنا الصارم
when we forced you to drink and drive a car without brake fluid!
بعدما ندفعه للشرب ونجعله يقود !سيّارة بلا زيت مكابح
And then you went after all six people who took part in it?
وبدأت باستهداف الستّة المشاركين في تلك المكيدة؟
The statute of limitations for murder is fifteen years.
الحدّ الزمني القضائيّ لجرائم القتل هو 15 عاماً
So I decided that if the law can't punish them, I would!
!لذا قرّرت أن أطبّق العدالة عليهم مكان القانون
I'm sorry I dragged you into this, Heiji-kun.
آسفٌ على إقحامك في هذا يا هيجي-كن
D-Don't talk like that!
لا-لا تقل كلاماً بائساً كهذا
You're a cop! You're the only ones in Japan allowed to carry guns!
أنت ضابط شرطة، الوحيدون المسموح لهم !بحمل مسدّس في اليابان
Why don't you feel any pride for that?!
لمَ لم تفتخر بذلك؟
Get up, Sakata!
!انهض يا ساكاتا
You put the cherry blossom emblem on your notebook to shame!
!شعار زهرة الكرز في دفتر مذكّراتك يبكي
O-Otaki-san...
...أ-أوتاكي-سان
How's Heiji-kun?!
كيف هيجي-كن؟
They took him away in another ambulance just now.
نقلوه بسيّارة إسعاف أخرى للتو
He's really something. He carried you out of that fire, on his back.
إنّه شابٌ مذهل، اندفع من النار وهو يحملك على ظهره
Yes...
أجل
Is this the homicidal maniac who tried to kill me?!
!أهذا هو؟! المجرم الذي حاول قتلي؟
Why, you--!
!تبّاً لك
He is still my subordinate. Hands off.
لا يزال تابعي حالياً، لا تمدّ يدك رجاءً
O-Old man Toyama!
!سـ-سيّد توياما
I'll pay a visit later, Goshi-san.
سأزورك لاحقاً يا غوشي-سان
When I do, we can talk about what happened twenty years ago.
عندها يمكننا الكلام بشأن الحادثة القديمة قبل 20 عاماً
Heiji, hang in there.
!هيجي! تماسك
Heiji.
!هيجي
How bad is Hattori-kun's injury?
كيف هي إصابة هاتّوري-كن؟
We don't know yet.
لا ندري بعد، علينا استخراج الرصاصة بأسرع ما يمكن حالياً
The bullet?
!الرصاصة؟
Did Sakata-san shoot you?
هل أطلق عليك ساكاتا-سان؟
He didn't shoot me.
لم يطلق عليّ
I happened to get hit while stopping him from killing himself.
بل حاولت منعه من الانتحار، وأُصبت عرضاً أثناء ذلك
Why would you do something so dangerous?
لمَ؟ لمَ تقدم على أمرٍ خطر كهذا؟
Because some idiot told me
أخبرني أحمقٌ ما أنّه لا يجدر بك دفع المجرم إلى الموت باستنتاجاتك
Hattori...
...هاتّوري
Dang, I'm starting to feel sleepy.
كلا
Let me rest a minute.
دعوني أنم قليلاً
Don't! You can't sleep, Heiji!
!كلا! لا يمكنك النوم يا هيجي
Heiji?
هيجي؟
No...
!كلا
Heiji!
!هيجي
Shut up!
!اصمتي
Didn't you hear me say I wanted to get some rest?
ألا تفهمين عندما أخبرك !بأن تتركيني أنام يا حمقاء؟
If you're got this much energy, you should be fine.
أظنّه بخير إن كان بهذه الحيويّة
I didn't get much sleep because I've been coming up with a good tour of Osaka last night.
لم أنم كفايتي البارحة لانشغالي بالتخطيط لجولة أوساكا
Don't go screaming creepy nonsense into my ear,
فلا تزعجيني بنحيبك، ساذجة
Sorry my voice is so creepy.
اعذرني على نحيبي المزعج
What are you doing, moron?
!ما الذي تفعلينه يا حمقاء؟
You're the moron!
!أنت الأحمق! من يرقد بذاك الشكل المربك؟
Come on, you two.
...هـ-هوّنا عليكما
I'm injured over here!
!افهمي! أنا مصاب
This guy won't be dying anytime soon.
لا أظنّه سيلقى منيّته في أيّ وقتٍ قريب
Don't!
!توقّف
Don't do it, Conan-kun!
!كلا يا كونان-كن
Huh?
ماذا؟ لمَ؟
This was definitely a murder.
كانت هذه جريمة قتل كليّة
Someone planned it from the start.
من تدبير أحدهم منذ البداية
Next Conan's hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Model gun.
مسدّس مقلّد
Next episode airs on October 12th. Read a copy of Shonen Sunday...
تُبث الحلقة القادمة في الثاني !عشر من أكتوبر
While you wait.
!كونوا بانتظارنا